Munish Bali

271, 250 Sunny Meadow Blvd., Brampton, Ontario 6478949126 munishbali50@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/munish-bali-820b80170

January 24, 2023

Ms.XYZ Senior Software Developer Ontario IT Consulting Inc. 012-xyz Canada

RE: Software Developer intern

Dear Ms. XYZ,

It is with great interest that I submit my cover letter and resume in response to your exciting opportunity as a **Software Developer intern** which was advertised on your company's website. I have experience with software programming in C and Java. I am completing an Advanced Diploma in Software Engineering Technology in April 2024 and also hold a Bachelor of Technology – Computer Science.

During my previous work terms, I have gained extensive abilities in software designing. As a Java Software Developer at Coforge Itd., I worked with the core developer team to provide efficient software to our clients. Furthermore, as a Software developer in Coforge Itd., I have worked on HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Hibernate, Spring Boot, Postman, Tomcat, Github, and Angular. The attached resume includes more information about my technical skills and experiences related to the available position.

I understand that Ontario IT Consulting Inc. has received numerous business awards for its outstanding products and services. I would be proud to be a part of your innovative team and to contribute my existing knowledge and skills in this field.

I would welcome the opportunity to attend an interview to discuss my qualifications for this position in person. Thank you for your time and consideration.

Sincerely,

Munish Bali

Munish Bali

271, 250 Sunny Meadow Blvd., Brampton, Ontario 6478949126 munishbali50@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/munish-bali-820b80170

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

TESTING SUPPORT | JAVA FULL STACK | CONSUMER FOCUS

- Experience designing and developing various kinds of robust software applications.
- Familiar with C, Java, J2EE, Hibernate, Oracle, MySQL Server, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Maven, Git and Postman.
- Knowledgeable in rich Internet applications, mobile computing and software security
- Specializes in object-oriented software design, user-oriented interface design.
- Excellent problem solver with strong analytical skills used to troubleshoot issues
- Multilingual in English, Hindi and Punjabi; uses strong communication skills to support clients and relay technical solutions to coworkers

KEY SKILLS

Java	Spring Boot	Hibernate
С	HTML	Css
MySql	JavaScript	Postman
Git	Replit	Bootstrap

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Technology Co-op Diploma

Sept.2022- Present

Centennial College, Toronto, ON a GPA of 3.3/4.5

Expected graduation: Apr.2024

Currently maintaining

Academic Projects:

• Started working on a personal website which will help upcoming student regarding accommodation, financial literacy and Canadian education podcasts etc.

Bachelor of Technology – Computer Science

Sept.2016-Apr. 2020

Rayat Bahra University, India

RELATED WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Engineer

Aug. 2021 – April 2022

Coforge Itd, Noida,

- Programmed various new sections of the financial website and oversaw the testing phase of the system
- Assisted with developers in the designing of a robust and reliable website for Lincoln Financial Group.

Graduate Engineer Trainee

Coforge Itd., Noida, India

Jan.2021 - Aug. 2021

Trainee (Internship)

Jan-July. 2020

QSpiders, Chandigarh, India

- Tested new interactive games thoroughly using company's standard testing procedures
- Documented testing results accurately and diligently
- Participated in and contributed ideas in weekly meetings with colleagues on game upgrades and improvements

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Support Representative (Co-op Work Term)

Sept. - Dec. 2022

Centennial College, Toronto, ON

- Answered students' computer questions over the phone using clear and engaging communication
- Supervised student computer labs to ensure the equipment was in good working order and to resolve students' technical problems

Sales Associate (Part-time)

Oct. 2022 - Present

Mr. Lube Store, Toronto, ON

- Provided quality customer service to individuals from diverse backgrounds
- Assisted customers with locating and selecting merchandise by maintaining updated knowledge on products within the store
- Handled cash transactions accurately and efficiently

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Iravati Foundation -Full time

Jan. 2016 - Present

India

- Social worker
- Help people who are in needs, provide them shelter, food and also help them with medical aids.